# JEUEL VIVEROS

Dallas, TX 75218

Phone: 214 783-7757 | Email: vjeuel@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeuel-viveros-9713aa191/ | Github: https://github.com/vjeuel |

Portfolio: https://vjeuel.github.io/portfolio 2/

#### SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer at Southern Methodist University. Having owned a restaurant for 17 years acquired experience in public relations, finances, advertising and training. Graphic Designer experienced in designing advertising materials for various businesses. Known as a creative, is also adaptable, disciplined and loves a challenge. Proficiency with HTML, CSS, jQuery, Node.js, MySQL and studying across the full technical stack. Excited to keep learning in the future and looking forward to solving problems since I have an ability to think out of the box. Fluent in Portuguese and Spanish.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3.

**Applications:** jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, Sequelize, Handlebars, Express, MySQL and MongoDB.

### **PROJECTS**

## Hungry at Home | https://github.com/vjeuel/food\_api\_app | https://vjeuel.github.io/food\_api\_app/

- Website designed around the idea of helping people who are at home in a Covid-19 lockdown, to give them access to meals and drinks recipes and also to stay connected with news related to the virus.
- Responsible for the design, using CSS's Media Query in conjunction with Materialize framework and also helped with the API's connections.
- HTML5, CSS3, Materialize CSS and Javascript.

## Weather APP | https://github.com/vjeuel/weather\_app | https://vjeuel.github.io/weather\_app/

- Responsive website that offers weather information and 5 days forecast, a particular feature is that, depending on the weather, the background changes accordingly to the weather condition.
- Responsible for the design, connecting the 3 API's and making it responsive with CSS grid and flexbox.
- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and jQuery.

## RUI | https://github.com/vjeuel/Digital-Menu-Project | https://tinyurl.com/y6rpjktz

- Web application that offers restaurants online ordering capabilities.
- Responsible for the design, connecting Passport and using CRUD operations with Sequelize.
- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Sequelize, MySQL, Handlebars, Shoelace and Passport application.

#### EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer | Freelancer | Dallas, TX | 2000 to Present Tony's Pizza and Pasta | Owner-Operator | Dallas, TX | 2002 to 2019

#### **EDUCATION**

**Full Stack Web Development Certificate:** Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX, 09/2020 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.is, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars & React.